talis.com 2005-12-13

# Privacy policy for the Talis web site

The purpose of this statement is to inform users of this web site what information is collected about them when they visit this site, how this information is used and if it is disclosed. Talis is committed to protecting your privacy.

**1.   Data Protection Statement**

> 1.1. In using and submitting forms on this web site you agree that the Talis may use any personal data of yours that you supply through the forms. Talis respects your privacy and seeks to protect your personal data by:
>
>> 1.1.1. only collecting and using your information to administer, support, improve and obtain feedback on its services; 
>> 
>> 1.1.2. using this information to assess what Talis products and services may be of interest to you and to personalise our service and marketing; 
>> 
>> 1.1.3. contacting you to obtain feedback on services and any improvements that can be made to them; 
>> 
>> 1.1.4. informing you that you have the right to ask Talis at any time not to contact you by way of direct marketing; and 
>> 
>> 1.1.5. not disclosing your personal data to any other organisations without your permission. 

**2.   What information does Talis collect? **

> 2.1. Talis collects email addresses and on some parts of the site Talis asks you to register, and if you do Talis asks for your name, email address, postal address and other personal information. 

**3.   Use of Cookies **

> 3.1. Cookies are small files which many web sites transfer to your hard disk. They can inform the web site what pages you visit, and your preferences, which enable web sites to provide you with a more personalised service. You can set your browser to refuse cookies, or to warn you before accepting them.

> 3.2. Talis use cookies, but most parts of Talis' web site can be accessed even if your cookies are turned off. But you may find there are parts of the site which you cannot access if your cookies are turned off.

**4.   How does Talis use your information? **

> 4.1. Talis uses the information to help understand more about how the web site is used, to improve the web site, and to send you information about Talis and its products which Talis think may be of interest to you, both electronically or otherwise.

> 4.2. By completing the on-line registration form, you consent to the use of your email address by Talis for the purposes of sending you information, updates, newsletters and details of events being held by Talis. You may unsubscribe from this service at any time by emailing [marketing@talis.com](mailto:marketing@talis.com).

> 4.3. Unless you have informed Talis that you do not wish to receive further information about its products, Talis may send you direct mail.

**5.   When does Talis share information? **

> 5.1. Talis does not sell your personal information to others.

> 5.2. If you sign up for services that are managed or offered by other organisations, they will obtain your information.

> 5.3. A number of other people's web sites have links on Talis' site. If you link to their sites, they may collect information. Such sites are not within the control of Talis and are not covered by this privacy statement.

6.  If Talis believe that your use of the site is unlawful or damaging to others, it reserves the right to disclose the information it has obtained through the site about you to the extent that it is reasonably necessary in Talis' opinion to prevent, remedy or take action in relation to such conduct.
